Charles Wu

UX Designer & Developer

1-647-767-6126 ☐ charleswu.ca ☐ im.charles.wu@gmail.com ➤

Summary

A versatile and agile user-experience designer & developer, adept in research, planning, and converting user needs into product requirements. He is efficient at converting designs into tangible results through the means of prototypes, animation, and code.

Experience

UX Developer

Sep 2016 - Present

CareerJSM, Toronto

- Designed and implemented prototypes for stakeholders to demonstrate new Job Search Management application features
- Conducted web accessibility audit and performed necessary design and code updates to meet WCAG Level-A requirements
- Planned and implemented user testing sessions to validate features

UX Developer

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

DIVE Networks, Toronto

- Led company UX training sessions to enhance product direction
- Optimized visual content for web and TV displays, factoring in content size, speed, and viewer distance
- Created user personas and use-cases to enhance functionality and usability for key audiences
- Developed an automation script to isolate anomalies by analyzing visual differences

UX Designer & Developer

Jan 2015 – Jun 2015

Crowd Curio, Waterloo

- Improved user engagement by testing and optimizing different layouts, and through added gamification elements
- Created information architecture maps, wireframes, and prototypes

UI Designer

Jun 2014 – Aug 2014

McKinsey Digital Labs, New York

- Produced wireframes, storyboards, and mock-ups, making use of user research and user-centered design principles
- Consulted with clients to translate business requirements into feature sets and designs

iOS Developer & Product Designer

Jan 2013 – Apr 2013

AlphaBroder (formerly Ash City), Richmond Hill

- Independently managed, designed, and developed a mobile catalog and ordering app, from conception to delivery within a 4 month deadline
- Organized and led one-on-one user testing sessions

Skills

UX: User Research, User Testing, Wireframing, Information Architecture Design, Prototyping (Adobe CS, Sketch, Axure), Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)

Dev: HTML, CSS (SCSS, BEM), JS (Vanilla, Ember), Python, Java, Git

Education

Bachelors of Applied Science (BASc), University of Waterloo

2010 - 2015

Systems Design Engineering, Option in Management Science

Projects and Interests

Projects

- Curio-X: Designed and optimized a citizen science and gamification project to digitally catalog images
- BufferBox (acquired by Google): Led a team of 3 designers and marketers
- Proxima: Fabricated and tested a glove to wirelessly transfer data via gestures
- Focus: Built and published a study tool
- InFit: Developed a fitness tracking app to process biometric data

Volunteer

- Engineering Society Class Rep for Systems Design 2015
- Orientation Week Director 2013-2014

Recreation

In my free time, I enjoy rock climbing, photography, volleyball, biking, cooking, and traveling. I also work on my Android app which uses AI and machine learning to improve personal schedules.